[light music]
You did it!
Subaru, that was amazing.
Whoever thought all
this up was pure evil.
Huh?
That's the first thing you say?
Nothing about
that exam was fair.
Only people who know
the same sky I do
would even have a chance
at getting it right.
So why ask it?
The more I learn about
this master of yours,
the more I get the idea he
must have been a real jerkwad.
Oh, come on now.
How can you say that,
and so seriously?
It's not good to say such
mean things about yourself, OK?
[sighs]
Putting all that aside,
this sure is
an awful lot of books.
I'm so curious to see
what's inside of 'em.
From the way
Ms. Shaula described it,
it's a treasure trove,
one of endless wisdom.
But--
[SHAULA squeals]
Based on her
current reaction,
this is the first time she's
ever seen this archive opened.
We'll have to find what
we're looking for ourselves,
I suppose.
Subaru, the riddle
was only solved by you.
So is it OK for anyone other
than you to touch these?
Yeah.
but, you know, if they made it
so only the one who answered
could read them,
would the rest of you
really have been
allowed to enter?
Oh, you're right.
For us to have gotten inside,
this place must have
granted us the access.
[eerie music]
[gasps] Hey, look,
the letters are scrambling.
I can't read them at all.
This one's doing
the same thing over here.
It's a form
of cognitive obstruction.
But I can still read
the titles, I suppose.
This one's Noah Libertas.
This one says Aegon Voller.
They don't appear to be
in any kind of order either.
Those titles,
do you think it's possible
they're all people's names?
Ah.
Yes, it looks like it.
How strange.
Glancing them over, I don't
quite recognize any of them.
Of course, that may change
if I look at all of them, but--
This sucks.
What's the point in a bunch of
books if no one can read 'em?
Huh?
Hey, isn't this--
Subaru?
[eerie music]
♪ ♪
[gasping]
[screaming]
[NARRATOR]
A woman,
there was a lone woman,
a young woman,
so young I'd hesitate
to call her a woman,
but a woman nonetheless.
[thumping]
[gasps]
[FATHER]
Typhon, let's go.
[NARRATOR] Her entire world
was black and white,
good and evil,
righteous or wicked.
And the one who divided
them up was her father.
[crowd cheering]
He was in charge
of punishing criminals,
delivering consequences
befitting of their crimes.
He was the scale that decided
what was good
or evil in their world,
a form of justice
he had hoped to teach her.
But she wasn't
able to understand.
[grunts]
There was no simple answer
to judging good versus evil,
for crime and punishment
were influenced
by many different factors.
But then--
No, wait.
[glass breaking]
[whimpering]
[door opens]
[FATHER]
Huh?
I'm so sorry, Father.
I dropped it, and it broke.
Hmm.
[whimpering]
You are right to confess
your crime to me,
as well as apologize
the way you did.
[chuckles]
Huh?
[NARRATOR] At that moment,
she finally understood.
The scale that weighed
the gravity of a crime
could only be
found in one place,
and that would be
within the heart
of the one who committed it.
Hey, mister!
Did you do something bad?
Huh?
Have you committed a sin?
[cracking]
[shatters]
[screams]
Did you also do
something that was bad?
[gasps]
Did you commit a sin?
[cracking]
[shatters]
Who here has done
something bad?
[shattering]
Father, are you a sinner?
Weren't some of the things
you did bad too?
Typhon!
[wind blowing]
[NARRATOR]
She understood everything,
and she was content.
For now, she had at last
acquired the scale.
The Witch of Pride went
on to question people's sins,
deal punishment, and judge
criminals for their wrongdoing.
[screams]
Subaru!
You all right?
It looked like you were
really in a lot of pain.
Did-- did I manage to avoid
letting it take me away?
I'm still actually here, right?
Typhon?
Is that a name you're
familiar with, I suppose?
Yeah.
Are you nuts?
[BEAKO]
What a rude thing to say.
It's no different from any
of the other books, I suppose.
However, you experienced
something else entirely.
That's how I
perceived it, at least.
Guess so.
But then what about
this book is so special?
This Typhon person was
someone you'd heard of before?
It's hard to explain it.
I mean, if you
don't know who she is,
then that must mean
you didn't meet her before.
It was at the graveyard.
The graveyard?
She was one
of the witches from the past,
the Witch of Pride,
a tan-skinned girl
as young as Beako.
And she-- she was like
the living manifestation
of pure and innocent cruelty.
That book had me experience
what I think were
her old memories,
her life, or roots?
Whatever it was, I
experienced all of it with her.
It sure didn't feel good.
And that's putting it lightly.
You lived someone's
memories through their eyes?
The more you say,
the more it sounds like
the trial in the graveyard.
Yeah, except that time, it
wasn't someone else's memories.
You had to face
your own head on.
But that was a piece
of cake, really.
Yeah, easy peasy,
lemon squeezy.
Well, putting you
two's tough act aside,
you can relive someone else's
memories through this book.
You could also look at it as
a means of retracing the past,
I suppose.
When you consider that, the
claim you can find anything you
want to know in this library--
[grunts]
[thud]
Julius!
Julius, hey,
keep it together.
You can hear
my voice, can't you?
[gasps]
Ms. Anastasia, did you--
Good.
Just keep on breathing
slowly and deeply.
You're gonna be just fine, OK?
Could your poor brain not
handle these impossible books?
Look at you,
trying to be clever.
Hey!
Ow!
Don't be such a buttface.
Julius, are you sure you're
going to be all right?
I am.
I'm very sorry
for making you worry.
That said, it wasn't
particularly soothing
for my heart.
Wait. Do you mean the same
kind of thing happened to you?
Yes.
[ANASTASIA]
Balleroy Temeglyph.
I think I remember
there being a general
with that name related
to the Vollachia Empire.
He was a former general,
to be more precise,
a remarkable and virtuous
warrior of unparalleled skill.
I faced him one on one
and somehow walked
away with my life.
But it was only
by a hair's breadth.
[BEAKO]
That confirms my suspicions.
Huh?
One must be familiar with the
author to read a book in here.
Also, they contain glimpses
only of lives past lived,
I suppose.
That seems like a fair
assessment so far.
Wouldn't that mean all
of the books in this library
are labeled with the countless
names of all those
who have died in this world
since the very beginning?
That's going to make this hard.
If you're right,
it's going to take forever
to find the one
book about whoever
you wanted to look for here.
Hmm.
Whoever made
a library like this
really was the biggest jerk
who ever lived.
[MEILI]
Man, oh man.
This all feels
so overwhelming at this point.
Between this and the riddle,
has enough happened
that you're finally interested
in being fully involved?
I'm not sure about that.
But basically,
you're at an advantage
if you know a lot
of dead people.
Then you'd be able to read
more of these books at least.
There might be
quite a few of them
for me to stick
my nose in then.
Books of the dead.
Huh?
[giggling]
Nope.
[whimpers]
[giggles]
Oh, I can't
believe you, Subaru.
You're such a terrible man.
That's a lot more
painful coming from you.
I'd much rather it come
from Ram or Anastasia.
[giggles]
This might be weird
timing, but can I ask you
some questions about yourself?
Ugh.
I think you have a few too many
romantic interests, though.
That's not what I meant!
So can you listen to me?
I'm messing with you.
If there's something you
really want to know about me,
just go ahead and ask.
I'll take you up
on that offer then.
For starters, how long have you
been working as an assassin?
Huh?
Since I first started
doing this job,
I figure it's been
five or six years.
Although in my case, I didn't
exactly consider it working.
It was more about my mom,
the one who took me in,
and following all her orders.
Hang on a sec.
Are you saying you
were an orphan?
Yep, thrown out
like trash as a kid.
I was abandoned
in some forest
when I was too young
to be aware yet,
and the Mabeasts there
raised me up big and strong.
[SUBARU] There are Mabeasts
that would raise a human baby
and not just kill it?
[MEILI]
Well, not any normal baby.
But I was born already
having the ability
to befriend Mabeasts,
so it was different for me.
At least I'm pretty sure
that's what saved my life.
Though, honestly, I think
my divine protection
was the reason my family
dumped me in the first place.
Kind of hard to know if it was
a good or bad thing, you know?
[giggles]
Hey, Meili, I'm just being
hypothetical here, but--
What's up?
It's just, if your parents'
books were here,
would you read them?
My parents, huh?
And by that, you don't
mean my mom, right?
Like my actual parents?
[SUBARU]
Yeah.
[MEILI]
No interest in that at all.
[SUBARU]
Really?
[MEILI] Don't get the wrong
idea about my reasons.
First of all, I don't feel
any anger towards them
for dumping me
or anything like that.
To be honest with you,
they're not even worth
that much to me, so.
Anyway, if I'd said that I
was interested in reading
their death books, then
what would you have done?
I would have looked
for them, obviously.
I mean, I can't promise
I would be able to find
them right away or anything.
But if you want to look
into it and find their names,
I could, I don't know,
make time to--
You really are the biggest
idiot on the whole planet,
aren't you?
What was that for?
[giggles]
So I had a thought.
Huh?
How do you think that more
books get added to the shelves?
Hmm.
Let's say, like,
if something were to happen
and you drop dead
right here and now,
would a book with
your name just
suddenly appear
out of thin air?
Now that piques
my interest for sure.
Sorry, but I can't
exactly test that out
for your entertainment's sake.
[EMILIA] Sounds like
you two are having fun.
So did you find something?
Unfortunately, no, we didn't.
How about you guys?
No, I'm really sorry.
We've taken
a look around,
but the books aren't
arranged in any sort
of order we figured out.
They're certainly not
in order of name or date,
at the very least.
Put simply,
all we were able to find out
is that we still don't
understand a thing.
[SUBARU]
Yes, that's it.
At least for the time being,
this archive is more
than we can deal with.
Hmm.
Even if we try our best
to find a name we recognize,
that person might not
even have the information
we're searching for.
And that makes a difficult
situation really difficult.
In that case, we should
turn our attention elsewhere.
Perhaps we're better off
taking the next exam
for entry into
the second level.
Yes, I agree.
But we've explored
a lot of this area.
So where is the stairway
leading to the next level?
Good point.
I haven't seen one.
Considering
the jerk responsible,
it seems possible finding
the stairs is part of the exam.
A jerk, huh?
Shaula!
Come here.
Oh, Master!
Roger!
I'm on my way.
What's the dealio?
Is there something that you'd
like me to do for you, Master?
When you come up right
to me with your eyes
all sparkling wide like
that, it makes me feel bad.
But, well, we've been
looking for the stairway
to the second level.
Do you know where we might--
- Not a clue.
I ain't ever been up higher
than the fourth floor before.
In 400 years?
Wow, that's really surprising.
Shaula, can I
ask you something?
You've been kept
in charge of watching over
this place for all this time.
You're the keeper of the
Great Pleiades Library, right?
Exactamundo.
All right then.
If I had to make a guess,
I'd say there's four--
no, maybe five?
Hmm?
I'm talking about
the number of secret rules
you were given to make sure you
properly protected this tower.
It's five, ain't it?
[squeals]
What do you mean?
And they're
secret ones at that.
What's all this about?
[SHAULA] It's not what
you're thinking, Master.
I'm not trying to be sneaky
or hide anything from you.
I just didn't mention it
because you didn't ask before.
I want to get that
in writing right away.
So you can't go after me, OK?
Whatever.
Just spill it.
Well, this is just
a hypothetical example.
But if you tried to leave
this tower at any time
without telling me first,
then I'd show no mercy
in killing you
and your companions.
That escalated quickly.
It's not like I want
to kill you or anything.
It's just an example.
Besides, I don't have
any say in the matter.
It's one of those things
I just can't get around.
It's seriously exhausting.
If you hate it that much,
why not refuse?
[gasps]
Hold on.
Don't tell me you have
some kind of contract?
If that's true,
then does that mean
you're a spirit like Beako?
Come on.
That's obviously not the case.
Honestly,
it's insulting that you'd go
and compare me to flaky
little things like fairies.
Why you gotta do me like that?
No, I am absolutely--
uh, huh?
You're all really
freaking me out right now!
Just so you know,
about 80% of us here
have connections
to fairies, by the way.
But if you're not a fairy,
then what are you?
If you're not a spirit,
what reason could you
possibly have
to cling so desperately
to a contract like that?
What are you saying, Subaru?
Huh?
Even if she isn't
a spirit or spirit user,
that wouldn't change
the fact that she still
has to keep her word.
OK, I admit that I could
have worded that better,
but it's just a figure of--
Promises are important.
And go.
Oh, damn it,
I got yelled at by Meili.
This is all your fault
for being so dodgy.
Out with it!
Wow!
Heck of a false accusation.
Well, that's my master for you.
All right, I'll talk.
OK, I will now give you
a simple explanation
of the orders I was given.
So listen up.
First, challengers
to the Great Pleiades Library
cannot be allowed
to leave after they start.
So that means we're all
stuck here right off the bat.
However, if you
pass all the exams
and reach the first
floor, it's no problem.
You can come and go
as you please.
Yay!
All Gucci.
Hmm?
[SHAULA]
Just so you know,
if anyone messes up
and violates these terms,
I'll be forced to transform
into a heartless
killing machine instantly.
And the promise I made
to you before will be voided.
I'll have to kill you.
I guess
your rules rank higher
than making me a promise.
Man, that hurts.
Wowee, I managed
to hurt my master.
I guess I've leveled up,
no doubt about it.
I've become stronger.
No, I've evolved!
This is my final form!
It's sarcastic!
Yeah, same here.
Anyway, moving on,
I'm bored now,
so I'll make this quick.
Rule one, leaving before
completing the exams
is forbidden.
Two, violating any of
the rules in any of the exams
is forbidden.
Three, disrespecting
the archive is forbidden.
Four, actions intended to
damage the tower are forbidden.
Five, uh-- there is no five.
So all in all, there
are four rules then.
But well--
Still can't help but be
suspicious of the one
about violating
the rules of the exams.
There are likely more rules
we don't know about,
ones that fall under
rule two but are hidden.
Sure that's all
the rules you were given?
Everything else is
fair game then, ain't it?
Yeah, I swear.
And there was no lying.
Also as long as none
of these rules are broken,
then, well,
my body belongs to me!
It's all mine.
Oops, no!
I mean, belongs to you.
Uh, nah.
What, you don't want me?
But my heart
belongs to you forever.
So take it!
Don't want that either.
Either way, if we aren't
able to leave the tower
unless we pass all the exams,
it's a lot like the trial
at the graveyard.
Hmm?
Hardly.
If it comes down to it,
we can still leave
if we defeat her, right?
Easier than the graveyard.
My master would
never do that to me.
No, for he was
kinder and more
big hearted than anyone
else in the whole world!
Oh, crap.
This is bad.
Lying made me itchy all over.
OK, then, Meili, you're up.
Keep a nice tight hold
on Shaula's reins, will ya?
[MEILI]
You can count on me.
[groans]
You know, I've had some time
to think a little bit now,
about how the person
who built this tower
wasn't a very honest person.
When I start looking
through that lens--
The way you phrased that
was just too adorable.
But you're right.
Go on.
It's about the possible
location of the stairway.
I have a hunch.
[footsteps approaching]
[gasps]
See, there they are.
Not that I had any doubts,
but whoever made this tower
was an absolute scumbag.
I'm impressed you managed
to figure it out, Ms. Emilia.
It wasn't on the
third floor, you know?
So that's why I figured
that it had to be hiding
in a place we'd already been.
Right, but then was
this stairway not actually
here when we were
down on this floor before?
It's also possible
it had been hidden
using a form
of cognitive obstruction,
I suppose.
[sighs]
Great!
I say it's time
we take this thing on,
show it who's boss,
and finish this.
Let's go, Beako!
[screaming]
S-Subaru,
hold on! Wait!
[BEAKO]
Put me down!
[screams]
Gotcha, gotcha,
gotcha, gotcha, gotcha!
That's enough!
Stop, I suppose!
Come on!
I said, stop!
Gotcha, gotcha,
gotcha, gotcha, gotcha,
gotcha, gotcha, gotcha!
[screaming]
[shouts]
[BEAKO yelps]
So it's another blindingly
white room, huh?
I suppose.
[sighs]
This again?
If this is the second
floor I was expecting, then--
The next exam should
be beginning shortly.
In fact, I'm guessing that
will be the trigger, I suppose.
I'm assuming that's supposed
to be some kind of selection
I need to pull out.
Here goes.
[sword clinks]
[grunts]
[eerie music]
[MAN] Fool who has attained
the heavenly sword,
you must now earn his pardon.
Fool who has attained
the heavenly sword,
you must now earn his pardon.
Fool who has attained
the heavenly sword,
you must now earn his pardon.
[screeching]
Emilia.
I understand.
Fool who has attained
the heavenly sword,
you must now earn his pardon.
Fool who has attained
the heavenly sword,
you-- you must now
earn his pardon.
Huh?
Fool who [stammers]
heavenly sword--
What the-- what's happening?
[groaning]
[shouting]
Master, Master,
Master, help me!
Shut the hell up!
I've got a massive hangover!
My head's pounding!
Quit your screeching!
[thud]
[gurgling]
[SUBARU]
You gotta be kidding me.
[sword clinks]
You are no ordinary man.
That is plain to see.
Huh?
Who the hell are you?
And where am I anyway, huh?
You messing with me or what?
I'm not.
I can assure you.
You appeared
before us suddenly.
Please understand that we
can't help but be wary.
The hell's your problem, kid?
Who do you think you are
talking to me like you're
my follower or something?
Are you my follower?
No, didn't think so!
So quit making everything
so damn complicated
for no reason, asshole!
Tch!
Hmm?
Hot chick,
hot chick, sexy chick,
brat, brat, follower, wuss.
I must apologize, but I am
not one of your followers.
Hah!
Every time you
open your mouth,
you sound more
like my follower.
Quit imitating them!
[sighs]
Ah, well, let's go then.
Hang on.
You've been yapping too much.
Would you just
slow down a little bit?
Oh, shut your trap.
I already explained every
damn thing you need to know
about this test here before.
You ought to learn
to listen better, kid.
What's that supposed to mean?
Fool who's attained
the heavenly sword,
you must now earn his pardon.
Hah!
Man, this hot chick's way
ahead of the wuss, clearly.
Ooh, now that I look
closer, you're really hot.
The hell's with that face?
It's way too
radiant to be legal.
- Radi--?
- All right!
So then you're
the examiner this time.
Am I right to assume that?
Don't know.
I don't really give a shit what
labels other people give me.
But if you're interested
in having a conversation,
then come try and make me
move one measly little step.
I am a proud part of the
Lugunica Imperial Knights,
Julius Euclius.
Afraid I ain't got no
name to give you, kid.
You can call me
a Stick Swinger.